Finding Aid for Michigan municipal charters
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan municipal charters 1913-1962
Michigan Historical Collections (collector)
94164 Cc 2
Municipal charters of various Michigan cities, some include amendments.
1 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Most of the collection was donated by C. F. Norton (donor 1862 ), with some other items added.
The collection is open without restriction.
The Michigan Municipal Charters collections was brought together by the Michigan Historical Collections from a variety of sources and accessions, principally from a donation by C. F. Norton.
Municipal charters of various Michigan cities, some include amendments. Some charters are cataloged separately in the MHC printed works catalog.
Subjects:
Alpena (Mich.)--Charters.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Charters.; Battle Creek (Mich.)--Charters.; Benton Harbor (Mich.)--Charters.; Birmingham (Mich.)--Charters.; Cadillac (Mich.)--Charters.; Dearborn (Mich.)--Charters.; Detroit (Mich.)--Charters.; East Ann Arbor (Ann Arbor, Mich.)--Charters.; Eastpointe (Mich.)--Charters.; East Lansing (Mich.)--Charters.; Gaylord (Mich.)--Charters.; Grosse Pointe Woods (Mich.)--Charters.; Hazel Park (Mich.)--Charters.; Holland (Mich.)--Charters.; Inkster (Mich.)--Charters.; Jackson (Mich.)--Charters.; Kalamazoo (Mich.)--Charters.; Ludington (Mich.)--Charters.; Marquette (Mich.)--Charters.; Midland (Mich.)--Charters.; Monroe (Mich.)--Charters.; Mount Clemens (Mich.)--Charters.; Mount Pleasant (Mich.)--Charters.; Muskegon (Mich.)--Charters.; Muskegon Heights (Mich.)--Charters.; Parchment (Mich.)--Charters.; Petoskey (Mich.)--Charters.; Pontiac (Mich.)--Charters.; Reed City (Mich.)--Charters.; Rochester (Mich.)--Charters.; Roosevelt Park (Mich.)--Charters.; Royal Oak (Mich.)--Charters.; Saginaw (Mich.)--Charters.; Saint Clair Shores (Mich.)--Charters.; Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.)--Charters.; Scottville (Mich.)--Charters.; South Haven (Mich.)--Charters.; Tecumseh (Mich.)--Charters.; Traverse City (Mich.)--Charters.; Troy (Mich.)--Charters.; Walled Lake (Mich.)--Charters.; Warren (Mich.)--Charters.; Wyoming (Mich.)--Charters.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)--Charters.
- Charters
  - Alpena 1944 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor 1956 (Box 1)
  - Battle Creek, proposed 1960 (Box 1)
  - Benton Harbor 1921 amended to 1945 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1954 attached.
  - Birmingham, 1933. Amendments to 1960 attached (Box 1)
  - Cadillac 1913 (Box 1)
  - Dearborn 1942 (Box 1)
  - Dearborn 1942 amended to 1957 (Box 1)
  - Detroit 1918 amended to 1944 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1945 attached.
  - East Ann Arbor, proposed 1946 (Box 1)
  - East Detroit, 1929. Amendments to 1958 attached (Box 1)
  - East Lansing 1944 (Box 1)
  - Gaylord 1949 (Box 1)
  - Grosse Pointe Woods, proposed 1950 (Box 1)
  - Grosse Pointe Woods, 1950. Amendments to 1960 attached (Box 1)
  - Hazel Park, 1942. Amendments to 1956 attached (Box 1)
  - Holland 1913 (Box 1)
  - Holland, 1950. Amendments to 1953 attached (Box 1)
  - Inkster 1952 (Box 1)
  - Jackson 1914 amended to 1952 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1961 attached.
  - Kalamazoo 1918 amended to 1941 (Box 1)
  - Kalamazoo 1918 amended to 1955 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1959 attached.
  - Ludington 1916 printed 1928 (Box 1)
  - Marquette 1951 (Box 1)
  - Midland 1944 reprinted 1961 (Box 1)
  - Monroe 1913 (Box 1)
  - Mount Clemens 1954 (Box 1)
  - Mount Pleasant 1921 amended to 1954 (Box 1)
  - Muskegon 1919 amended to 1951 (Box 1)
  - Muskegon Heights 1922 amended to 1955 (Box 1)
  - Parchment 1939 (Box 1)
  - Petoskey, 1924. Amendments to 1946 attached (Box 1)
  - Pontiac 1920 amended to 1958 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1950 attached.
  - Reed City 1957 (Box 1)
  - Rochester 1948 (Box 1)
  - Roosevelt Park 1946 (Box 1)
  - Royal Oak 1921 amended to 1957 (Box 1)
  - Saginaw 1936 amended to 1953 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1960 attached.
  - St. Clair Shores 1950 (Box 1)
  - Sault Ste. Marie, 1952. Amendments to 1953 attached (Box 1)
  - Scottville 1958 (Box 1)
  - South Haven, proposed 1955 (Box 1)
  - South Haven 1962 (Box 1)
  - Tecumseh 1953 (Box 1)
  - Traverse City 1940 amended to 1955 (Box 1)
  - Troy, 1955. Amendments to 1960 attached (Box 1)
  - Walled Lake 1954 (Box 1)
  - Warren 1956 (Box 1)
  - Wyoming 1958 (Box 1)
  - Ypsilanti, 1947. Amendments to 1960 attached (Box 1)